Hello.
Good day to you.
Are you heading by the overpass?
The second one?
Yes, the one after this.
Thanks.
What's that?
That item thats on the dash
This?
Is it some sort of n antitheft device?
Yeah, sort of.
It looks pretty interesting
Really? Are you at all familiar with
this sort of device?
It's sort of my line of work.
Trust me on this.
You have to be careful.
A cousin of mine, poor guy,
he left the house,
got in his car to go to work
only to notice
all 4 of his car's tires had been replaced by a stack of bricks the night before.
What kind of car?
Just a cheap model!
Honestly, stealing tires from such
a cheap old car!
If I were in charge of this country's laws,
I'd hang a couple of them
just to send a message on theft crimes
Hang them? You seem quick to condemn to death without
considering whose lives might in fact be at stake!
Maybe some poor guys did it out of desperate need!
I cant believe you'd say that!
Need? What are you talking about?
Maybe they were in desperate need of some kind!
Our driver here could argue that he also has needs as it were
And why not me too,
while we are at it
No excuse to steal from others and
make them less well off
What are you saying?
Would you like if it happened to you?
Would that be fun?
No, I wouldn't be happy
if it happened to me.
I'm just saying you're quick
to hand out death sentences.
We need to get to the actual root
of the problem in each instance.
If they took a couple of them...
No one's born a thief I say!
How the hell could you be so sure of that?
If they hang just a couple of men, to make an example
of them, others would quickly get the message.
I understand what you are saying, but I dont accept your
idea is a valid one
Circumstances arise, men find themselves involved in
a "crime" perhaps even without having intended to so become.
But to hang men over some car tires?
You arent saying what it is that
would really be sensible to do
Remember, that not that long ago,
men were hanged in our state for even being
found to have done much less than that.
Who cares about them? It might lessen crime
Spare me.
You're in another world!
Sure I heard they got hanged for serious crimes as
assault or whatever else of that nature.
And yet, you must realize that it has not made such crimes
disappear altogether
You're not making sense with that point.
No actual problems were in fact solved that way...
The laws of the land are prescribed according to the
application of religious rules known as sharia law here.
If such extreme punishments havent yet eliminated
crimes
it may be because they havent been fully been
enforced well enough
So relax dear lady!
So you think applying religiously based so-called
Sharia law is the panacea to our problems
by increasing the number of executions?
For gods sake, Iran has the greatest number of executions
annually on the planet - second only to China!
You call that a solution? I think not!
You havent accepted a damn thing Ive said!
You dont realize what youre suggesting
instead of sharia punishments wont work
The Parssian Hospital?
Straight ahead.
Straight and you get there.
No, that's the wrong way for Parssian!
Saadat Abad,
between Kaj Square and Farhang.
So I make a U-turn?
Yeah, go to Saadat Abad.
Mister...
you're not usually a Taxi driver, are you?
What do you mean?
You call yourself a cabbie!
I just dont think it sounds likely
Not if you dont even know how to get
to the Parssian Hospital - as you should!
Straight ahead...
I guess you're really down on your luck
to be trying to be in this line of work as cabbie
What's up?
I follow you,
but now that we're chatting,
may I please ask you a question?
Shoot, lady!
Are you employed?
What does this have to do with anything?
There could be a connection
When you defend an idea,
either you believe in it
or you believe it to otherwise be nevertheless,
in your interest to do so as you do.
It's not an unreasonable question to ask I think
So, what work do you do?
I could ask you the same rather than
go on with this seeming inquisition?
You'll answer if I do?
You first, maybe I'll respond equally
I'm a teacher.
It figures, aye Cabbie!
You work in fiction, lady.
Reading too many books
and spending days with kids
has made your opinions sound a bit too Pollyanna like
Even if you hadn't told me,
I'd have guessed.
Now tell me what you do.
My work is freelance.
I'll tell you my speciality later.
I'll get off there
after the lights, please.
How much?
No need to pay.
Youre kiddin
Well you're definitely not a pro as a cabbie I'd say
And you did get carried away a couple of times. But here's your pay
What exactly do you freelance at?
I'll get out and tell you...
You really want the truth?
I do.
I actually might just be a mugger! hows that!
A mugger?
Yes.
But I don't mug teachers
or cab drivers like him.
People who rob the tires off the cars of the poor
can't stoop any lower.
Losers of the worst kind.
Take my advice. Don't pity them!
God bless.
Unbelievable.
Where did he come from?
How are you?
Be there in 10 minutes. Okay...
10 minutes.
I'll get off a bit further on.
Here?
Yes, thanks.
Here's the fare.
Thank you.
I'll hire your taxi just for me.
- Shariaty?
- Sorry, no.
Mr. Panahi, I recognize you.
Even with the beret,
I recognize you.
Can you stop
so I can sit in front?
Thank you.
Thanks very much.
You're making a movie, right?
The man and the woman...
Take a left, thanks.
To Shahran.
They were actors, right?
Know how I figured it out?
His last line was
like in the coffee shop scene
in "Crimson Gold", wasn't it?
You, a cabbie? No way, Mr. Panahi.
Ajob like another.
Sure, but you're not in your element!
You really don't recognize me?
I must have forgotten.
I'm Omid.
Omid who?
Omid the video renter!
I used to bring you movies!
For your son, I mean. Not you.
You were there once.
I said “Hello, how are you?”
You said “Fine, dear boy!”
You wanted
"Once Upon a Time in Anatolia"
by Nuri Ceylan. I gave it to you.
Why are you sweating so much?
It's so hot.
You wanted another movie too,
remember?
I don't!
“Midnight in Paris”, Woody Allen!
- That was you.
- Of course!
It hasn't opened yet.
You haven't seen a thing!
I can bring you dailies
of movies in the making.
Call you back.
Put him in!
Chamran Hospital.
Why on earth Chamran?
Go to Milad. He's poor!
Where is it? How do I get there?
Go on, step on it.
What happened?
An accident.
I'm dying-n
A bike accident.
Not my fault.
I said he should be the one
with the helmet.
Some paper...
No, I want to write my will.
Please find some paper
to write what I must say.
What does he want exactly?
Write down what I tell you.
My wife doesn't get it.
According to law, she can't inherit.
At most she'll get a few turkeys.
She'll be homeless!
Drive faster! Go to the hospital.
A cell phone! You have one?
It's not to make a call.
I need a camera.
Turn it on.
Mine has no battery.
The camera...
Point it at me.
Film me!
God be my witness!
My name is Mohamadi Rabei,
born in Ramhormoz.
ID number 508,
issued in Ramhormoz.
Don't cry. They won't hear my voice.
Son of Amin,
sound of mind and body,
I leave my wife my house
in the Hassan Kahn area
Spring Street, lzadi Alley number 34,
and all my belongings.
Forgive me, God!
My brothers should leave her in peace.
They mustn't file a claim.
They must respect
this last will and testament.
I leave everything to my wife.
This testament
must be kept from my brothers.
It's hers.
She should keep it.
There is no God but Allah...
Help him out.
Give me a hand.
It's not necessary. Go with him!
She's coming back.
Please give me
the film of the will, sir.
I can't now. Call me later.
My card. I'll give it to you later.
Move your car. Ambulance coming!
Here you go.
Did he die?
He's fine. He was just scared.
He was in very bad shape.
He closed his eyes at the end.
This is he.
Is it you, madam?
No, ma'am.
Rest assured. This is my number.
Sure...
I'll call you as soon as I can.
Good bye.
Was it her?
The husband died?
Just to make sure.
She was checking the number.
You planned it all
and thought I wouldn't guess...
Damn, no more battery.
May I use yours to make a call?
Thanks.
Let me do the code.
Hi, how is it going? In 10 minutes.
Relax, I'll be there.
I had something to do.
What do you mean,
I keep saying in 10 minutes?
Okay...
I'll be there in 10.
Thank you very much.
The 6th street, please.
This is the 4th...
Get ready to take a left.
All the way to the end.
Pull up next to the white car.
Can you unlock?
Hello? Who is it?
Is this the taxi driver?
How can I help you?
I'm the woman
with the injured husband.
You took us to hospital.
Sure, I recognize you.
You've changed your number,
haven't you?
It's my husband's phone.
I wanted to tell you,
now that I'm in town,
can I come and get it?
Get what?
The video, obviously.
I thought he was better.
He is...
but you never know about tomorrow.
I'd like to keep it handy, just in case.
I'll let you know once I make a copy.
Don't call this number.
Call my cell.
Please don't forget.
I won't. Don't worry, I'll definitely call.
God bless you. Goodbye.
Mr. Panahi! Hi!
Please come inside.
I'm fine, thanks.
Have a look.
Go in. Relax, he's one of us.
I brought you "Walking Dead", season 5.
No zombie movies.
You asked for it.
For my family.
You asked for it. Here it is.
And I brought you
4 Hollywood blockbusters.
Mel Gibson...
No commercial stuff.
Art house?
Yeah, like what?
I have a Kim du...
Kim du who?
The Korean guy!
This is a rare old Kurosawa.
Just for you.
The last one I have.
Get it?
This is arty too.
Yes?
Wrong number. Who is it?
Hold on...
Mr. Omid, it's for you.
Who is it?
He didn't say.
Just a minute.
Keep on looking.
Mr.Panahi...
I'm confused about what to take.
It's hard to believe
you're partners with Omid.
- Who said we're partners?
- He did!
I've seen most of the famous classics.
Which new ones are worth watching?
Let's see.
I think all movies are worth watching.
Depends on your taste.
I feel bad. You should have come inside.
I'm fine.
This is good.
This too.
Can I ask a favor?
Sure.
I'm studying film. I have to make a short.
- What major?
- Directing.
- School of Arts?
- Yes.
I'm looking for a good subject.
I've seen movies, read lots of books
but can't find a good subject.
Listen,
those films are already made,
those books already written.
You have to look elsewhere.
It won't come just by itself.
What do I do? Where do I start?
This is the hardest part.
No one can tell you.
You must find it yourself.
Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
What did you pick?
These.
All these?
45 tomans.
I'll bring “Big Bang Theory” next week.
Okay...
Same time, next week.
Mr.Panahi,
I still wish you'd come in.
You're very kind.
Good bye.
So we're partners now?
The door is open.
Please give us a lift.
We're in a rush.
We've been waiting for a cab.
Where to?
Ali's Spring.
Ali's Spring...
- We're really late.
- Different directions!
Keep quiet!
Please, sir.
We have until noon.
Please take us.
I'll drive you closer.
He'll get out soon.
Wait a sec.
Use that door. I'll move my bag.
I hope we make it on time.
Scoot over.
Don't get the car wet.
You kept complaining
but we found a cab.
What if we're late?
Of course we won't be late.
It'll be fine.
Believe me...
I didn't mean to say that.
Usually he just takes a few videos.
This time he took so many.
It was because of you.
If you came along to my other clients...
you'd make a fortune.
As partners, right?
This a cultural activity too.
They don't show these movies in Iran.
How else can students see foreign movies?
Your own son!
Even you!
Without me, no more Woody Allen!
At home
it's just us.
Why shut the bathroom door?
No one to spy on your beautiful body!
It's not good to be too carefree.
Overly carefree people
get on others' nerves...
- You mean yourself.
- Yes!
You're always on edge.
Dear fellow, you can get off here.
Here?
You can catch another taxi here.
What do I owe you?
Keep it for your cultural activity!
- It's locked.
- I got it.
He doesn't give up.
Believe me,
I just meant it as a favor.
On my wife's life,
I meant no disrespect!
The best I could do.
You're too kind. Thanks...
Excuse me, is your clock right?
Let me check...
A few minutes behind.
How far is the spring?
Ali's Spring? Depends on the traffic.
Can we make it before noon?
I hope so.
We'll make it even with traffic?
I can't say.
Go faster
and we'll make it, God willing!
God willing?
We must be on time!
No later than noon!
Excuse me...
Most people spend the afternoon.
Why so early?
This isn't for fun. it's very serious!
These fish must be in the spring
exactly at 12.
Don't you get it?
Our lives depend on it.
In the water by 12!
Our lives depend on it!
Oh my God, the fish are dying!
Sir, hurry!
Please hurry! They're dying!
Too much emotion!
Hurry, they're dying!
Lift your foot.
They're dying!
Don't squash them.
Faster!
Pour it in.
Quick, put the fish inside!
Enough water!
They'll be fine.
Just a minute.
Is it dead?
Remove the glass.
He stands there, staring.
It's nothing...
The fish are fine.
They're fine.
I'm really very sorry.
The number you are calling
is not available.
They're not hurt?
AQai", my apologies.
I was listening to you
and got distracted.
Why are they so special?
They seem like normal fish.
They're anything but normal.
We've kept them for a whole year!
And now you throw them back
into Ali's Spring?
Why don't you get it?
You're not paying attention!
We took them from the spring
because we were born 5 years apart.
But both at noon!
We have to throw them at noon
into Ali's Spring
and get two new ones.
Or else we're dead!
Understand? Dead!
God forbid!
At noon or we die.
I have to make a call.
Sorry, you must get out
after the overpass.
I'll hail you another cab.
It'll be fast.
I have to be somewhere.
I must pick up my niece at school.
We beg of you.
We have to be there by noon!
If I don't get there,
she can't walk home alone.
We'll never make it before noon.
What's he doing?
No idea.
What the hell? Such a lousy driver.
No sense of direction. Can't even drive.
What's he doing?
I have no idea.
We won't get there on time.
He knows the way and drives faster.
We'll never make it before noon.
I apologize again.
What a moron.
Thank you very much.
Why did you come in this car for me?
I told everyone
my director uncle was coming!
Now no one will believe me!
Think at least about my reputation.
You always talk about discipline.
I've been hanging around for an hour!
And all you do is keep quiet and stare.
Excuse me, young lady.
And hello to you too!
Hello. Don't change the subject.
What do you tell my parents
if I get kidnapped?
I wouldn't worry about that.
No one could stand all your blabbering.
Hop in.
I have to meet an old neighbor of mine.
You keep promises
to everyone but your niece!
Maybe I should leave you
to your meetings?
I'd find my way
like the girl in your “Mirror” film.
Shall I go or shall I stay?
Your choice.
Meanie!
I was so excited to see you today!
You're late and
now you want to leave me!
I apologized.
You're the one who won't quit!
I was teasing you.
If I wanted to leave,
I wouldn't have waited.
Why was your phone off?
You want the truth?
Are you capable of it, just once?
Uncle, when did I ever lie to you?
Go ahead!
I knew you'd call with 1000 excuses
for not coming.
What if I got worried?
Granny taught me.
When she misses you,
she won't answer the phone.
Thinking she's sick, you go visit her!
How are you?
It's me, Panahi.
I'm really sorry to be so late.
No, I'm on my way.
Where are you right now?
Just give me a few minutes...
Pull over and wait.
I'm on my way.
He thought you called to cancel?
Butt out.
Why did you want to see me?
Not while you're driving.
Why not? We're here together.
Let's talk.
You're a hopeless case!
When you meet
with a smart, educated lady
first you take her for a frappacino,
ice cream
or something of the sort.
Then you talk.
So talk to me,
smart and educated frappacino lady.
Our film teacher
asked us to make a short movie
in a month.
I'll record you
so I remember everything.
You're looking for a story.
As Granny says,
you're sharp as a tack.
By the way,
when Granny came last,
we heard shouting.
It was the neighbors.
They were kicking out some people.
Turns out it was their daughter's suitor.
He threw his daughter's suitor out
during a fight?
The guy she was in love with
was Afghani.
The father didn't know.
When the boy came,
the father found out.
He threw him out of the house.
She was locked inside.
Still, he came back
and waited to meet her at the corner.
Her brothers beat him up several times
but he kept coming back.
And so?
Now, you're not being very sharp!
I filmed the whole thing!
You filmed it all?
The whole thing, from A to Z!
You made your movie.
Why look for a story?
You're something!
As a director,
you know it's un-distributable.
U n -wh at?
Un-distributable!
All filmmakers know that and you don't?
No way!
You intend to show it somewhere?
Of course!
In the Public Education Festival.
Parents are invited to the screening
and the movie they like most
gets money
to make something better
and more distributable!
Very nice!
Mr. Arash.
I just made a U-turn at the overpass.
Where are you exactly?
I just passed by Divist Dastgah.
The other side?
At the corner.
A whitish-beige car?
I see you. Just a sec.
It's been ages since you last met.
6 or 7 years.
Can I tell you the truth?
He doesn't look like your kind of friend.
His father was
a good friend of Grandpa's.
He's from our old neighborhood.
Come on in.
The famous Miss Hana!
How are you?
Fine thanks.
Your uncle has become impossible to see.
He's forgotten his old neighbor.
He never calls
or answers my calls either.
You like fruit juice?
Orange juice? Ice cream pie?
No, thanks.
Just like her uncle, always "No thanks"!
- Frappacino?
- Love it!
Come on, let's go.
Sorry I didn't ask you into my car.
There's someone.
I want this to be kept secret.
I'll leave you a minute to look at it.
What is it?
Have a look. You'll see.
Your friend is suspicious.
He said to leave my camera here.
He may want to kidnap me!
Want some CDs?
I have all the new stuff.
Andy, Shahriyar, Shamaeezadeh...
Local and diaspora artists.
Great stuff.
How much?
Just this one.
2 tomans.
There are two CDs.
Did you see it?
Were you hurt?
Nothing too serious.
When did it happen?
Last month.
The security camera had just been put in.
Can I see it again?
I'll show you from another angle.
This is the woman.
This is the man.
He hit me with a club.
They're husband and wife.
Married?
When he threw me against the wall,
his bandana slipped to the side.
I saw his eyes. I thought I knew him.
That's when I felt it.
What did you do?
What could I do?
Did you do anything, file a complaint?
Why not?
It was just after...
the news reports
about those criminals who got hanged.
I didn't have the heart to turn them in.
That was different.
They put the film on the news
to make a statement.
It's a different story.
It wasn't just that.
I recognized them.
The man and the woman.
I know them.
Since then,
I found out
they were under financial pressure.
I saw how the money they stole
helped solve their problems.
I just couldn't have them arrested.
I just couldn't.
When I see them, I get on edge.
It makes me choke.
I thought talking to you
might ease the pain.
I know you can't make movies anymore.
Perhaps one day
another director can use it.
Here you are.
Anything else?
It's him.
Who?
The thief.
You should have told me.
I really wanted to see his face.
What for?
I wanted to see
what a thief looks like.
Like me, like you,
like anyone around us.
How are you doing now?
Better.
Getting better.
Still in the neighborhood?
Sure. I'm still there.
Faithful to our roots.
I came once to visit.
I didn't recognize our street.
Everything had changed.
Buildings razed.
The people changed too.
You rarely recognize anyone you know.
Everything's different.
Nice seeing you, Jafar.
Same here.
Thank you for your time.
You're welcome.
Anything I can do?
I'm fine.
Just tell Hana to come back.
Thanks, man!
Sorry I can't help.
Good bye.
What nice people,
especially the orange juice guy!
Tell me,
what did he look like?
What do you mean?
Normal. Like everybody else.
So you want to make
a distributable movie?
This is what I was reading
when your phone rang.
Here we go.
Teacher said a distributable movie...
You filming or reading?
First, make a choice.
She said we have to respect
the following rules
to make a distributable movie.
Respect for the Islamic headscarf,
no contact between men and women,
avoid sordid realism,
avoid violence,
avoid the use of a tie
for good guys.
Avoid the use of Iranian names
Instead use the sacred names
of the Islamic saints.
Uncle, why won't you listen to me?
I am. I was thinking...
About what?
I was just thinking
how would we manage
with the old neighbor you just met.
Is he a good guy or a bad guy?
He has an Iranian name and a tie.
That was real life.
These rules apply to movies!
If we want him as a good guy in a movie,
what do we do?
We change him from head to toe!
You mean
make a new person from scratch?
Change his name into an Islamic one,
take off his tie...
He had no beard
but we can give him a small one.
Should I continue?
Go on.
Avoid discussing political
and economical issues...
That's enough.
My teacher said other things too.
She said we should use our judgment.
If we notice anything problematical,
it's up to us to censure it.
She said: "You know better".
My dear uncle...
Listen.
Stay put.
I'll be a minute.
Going to the bathroom?
Butt out.
Don't get out.
And don't open the door.
And don't talk to strangers.
What?
Just kidding! Can't you take a joke?
You, boy!
Hey you!
Come here!
Yeah, you!
No camera!
Come here!
No camera.
I saw you take that, over there.
What?
The money!
No money in the garbage.
The money that fell
from the groom's pocket!
The groom's pocket?
I didn't see anything.
I saw it myself
and I got it on tape!
I couldn't care less.
It fell on the ground.
I found it. Now it's mine.
I saw the groom drop it.
My film teacher told us
we have a month to make
a distributable movie.
You took the money
and made it un-distributable!
Go give it back to the groom.
In exchange I'll give you 5 tomans.
50 for 5?
No one's crazy enough to do that.
Don't worry about them.
Her makeup cost a fortune.
They can afford it.
I don't care about their money.
I care only about my movie.
Please, put the money back.
You're ruining my movie.
Put it back
and you'll become my film's hero.
I want to show
sacrifice and selflessness!
I'm begging you, please.
What the fuck
is sacrifice or selflessness?
I don't want to be a hero,
just give my dad the money.
I'm begging you, please.
Do it for your mother's sake.
I have no mother.
You may not have a mother,
but you used to love your mother.
Do it just to make your mother happy.
Please, just go put the money back.
You do it.
No, you have to do it.
You do it, I'll record it.
For God's sake, please.
Please...
You're so stupid!
Hurry, they're gonna leave.
Give it to him!
Hurry up!
Give it back!
Why are you so upset?
It's nothing.
Want to talk?
Don't ask. I don't want to elaborate.
Whatever you say, young lady!
Hear that too?
Hear what?
Do you hear that out there?
I was concentrating.
I didn't hear or see a thing.
Look, she's there!
Who?
The flower lady.
Where?
Don't you see?
The one who brings roses
when she comes to see you.
Hello there...
Jafar Panahi, our very own!
Where are you going?
I'll call you later.
Where to? I'll take you.
Sit up front.
But you have a little passenger!
Thanks,honey.
How are you?
Fine, fine, very good!
For you, sweetheart!
Thank you very much.
How are you doing?
What's up?
Here, of all places?
Where to?
Cabbie now?
Back in the driver's seat?
Looking for someone?
I heard a voice
right before I saw you.
I thought
I recognized my interrogator.
Many of my clients say the same thing.
They want to identify people
from their voices.
Advantage of blindfolds.
Always trying to pin down the voice.
Where to?
Paradise!
Paradise.
There's Paradise Street...
Oh! That paradise?
That paradise.
Those gentlemen have
exclusive rights to that Paradise.
Seriously where to?
I'm going towards Vanak.
Is it convenient?
I don't want to be a bother.
Let me guess.
Either you're visiting
a prisoner who just got out
or the family of someone just in.
I wish it were good news.
Ghonche Ghavami is now in prison.
The girl from the stadium?
Just like in your movie.
"Offside".
Ghoncheh Ghavami
attended a volleyball game.
There were other women.
All arrested.
Everyone was freed but her.
It's been 108 days.
Did she get to see the game?
No, they were arrested
outside the stadium.
She's been on a hunger strike
for 10 days.
Her mother visited her.
She tried to persuade her
to break her strike.
We sent messages too,
saying you're entitled
to do what you're doing.
You and I have been
on hunger strikes ourselves.
It's always our very last resort.
She's doing the same thing.
The mother goes with food
to convince her to eat.
They put the mother
in a room with cameras:
"Come here, convince Ghoncheh."
Their typical filmed interview.
Obviously.
"Tell the camera
"she was never on strike."
The mother goes totally berserk,
storms out,
tells them to keep their visiting hours.
She takes the food and leaves.
They give Ghonche a piece of paper
and say to write the same thing:
"I never went on hunger strike".
She refuses, rips it up
and says: "You can keep your visits!"
So that's the story.
I'm going to visit them now.
We'll see what we can do for her.
As of yesterday,
she's stopped drinking water.
We'll see what our options are.
What can we do?
I see.
How is your husband?
He's fine, busy working.
Not banned from work?
No.
I heard you got a 3-year suspension?
No more law practice?
I heard the bar association
voted to suspend me.
From practicing law.
I haven't received any legal notice yet.
For now... nothing.
It's not official until I get one.
The bar association did this?
I don't know.
Don't they defend lawyers' rights?
As if the Directors Guild
forbade you to make movies.
How would it feel?
It's wet back here.
Someone left a purse.
A purse? Show me.
Here.
See if there's an address or something.
That's wrong. It's not mine.
It's totally impolite.
Sorry I asked, young lady!
This purse doesn't belong
to someone my age.
Not even for my mother's age.
It belongs to an old lady.
Like Granny?
Exactly!
Maybe it was...
those women who went to Ali's Spring.
My only elderly passengers.
Ali's Spring...
You must find them.
You found your way.
First I'll drop you off.
Let me off here.
Take the Nawab highway.
Not far.
Totally opposite directions.
Do your thing. It's more important.
This is for the people of cinema.
Because the people of cinema
can be relied on.
Just like you.
I put it there.
Don't think I don't see
what you're up to.
You know, Jafar,
sometimes they do it on purpose
so we know they're watching us.
Such obvious tactics.
First they mount a political case.
You're an agent for Mossad, CIA, Ml5!
They beef it up
with a morality charge.
They make your life hell.
When you finally get released,
the outside world
becomes a bigger cell.
They make your best friends
your worst enemies!
Either you have to escape the country
or start hoping to go back to jail.
In my opinion... just let it go.
That's it.
Better to remove my words
from your movie.
You'll be accused of sordid realism.
They'll bother you even more.
It's green. Hurry.
Thanks, it was a pleasure.
Hurry up!
Get in the car.
Uncle, isn't she lovely?
The flower lady?
What exactly is "sordid realism"?
Wasn't it in your instructions?
Teacher even explained what it meant.
It didn't get it.
Bad explainer!
She said show what's real,
but not real real.
Then she said
if reality is dark and unpleasant,
not to show it.
Personally, I don't get the difference.
Real, unreal...
It's honestly beyond me.
Can't get it in my head.
Like the things
flower lady just said
shouldn't be shown or spoken of.
Nonsense.
Everything she said was real.
There are realities
they don't want shown.
They don't want to show it
but they do it themselves.
Whatever... I don't get it.
The flower is so pretty.
Let's see if they're here.
They're here.
Where's the purse?
In my backpack.
Hwg Q Om. Ins'
No memory stick.
We'll come back.
TAXI
A film by Jafar Panahi
The Ministry of Islamic Guidance
approves the credits
of distributable films.
Despite my heartfelt wish,
this film has no credits.
I am indebted
to everyone who helped us.
This film would not exist
without their support.